<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hans Engebretsen - Designer</title>
    <description>Internet prescence of Hans Engebretsen - purveyor of the internets graphic designer and web creative</description>
    <link>http://www.haaans.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.haaans.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Sketch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After dabbling in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; for a while, and toying with the idea of using for more than just a mobile mockup or two, I finally bit the bullet and used Sketch for everything on a (mostly interface-design) project. Sketch isn’t a replacement for Photoshop so much as it as replacement for a collection of things Photoshop is used for which it isn&amp;#39;t meant to excel at. Brushes, complicated masks, curves (photo editing features in general) and effects aren&amp;#39;t thing Sketch tries to replicate/replace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;negative-bullet&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; It’s a primitive product&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS is tested. Years of versions, millions of users, and bazillions of dollars. It’s easy to take that for granted after loosing an hour of work from a crash. Bohemian Coding has only been working on Sketch for 3 years; contrast that to a product that has been on the market for 25 years, and the difference is noticeable. In light of that, it’s fairly remarkable that they’re able to come up with something worthy comparing to PS (they even have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bohemiancoding.com/sketch/community/&quot;&gt;decent commmunity&lt;/a&gt;. That said, it clearly doesn’t have the flavor that a well-seasoned product like Photoshop does, but that’s okay - mostly because it also doesn’t carry the price tag that PS does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;negative-bullet&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; I miss the keyboard shortcuts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it – I just miss the keyboard shortcuts PS has that Sketch has replaced with a less-cryptic, (slower but more usable) interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;positive-bullet&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; It still hasn&amp;#39;t crashed on me&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS has a bad habit of crashing. It has effectively reinvoked my former muscle memory for command S. Combined with it&amp;#39;s pathetic recovery effort, it can be awefully frustrating. Despite having around twice as many elements in a given document, Sketch stuttered, but never lost my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;positive-bullet&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; Organization, Clean and Easy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me the most valuable use for Sketch is organization. Where I would have needed 10 PS files, 1 Indesign document, and countless inconsistencies, I was able to easily use single Sketch file. Leveraging cascading properties, and the seamless ways groups work allowed me to design on the fly. What I lost in functionality and learning curve, Sketch made up in time-saving file/style management.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/sketch/layers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of layers &quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;neutral-bullet&quot;&gt;+-&lt;/span&gt; Exporting, As it should be&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a heavily-touted feature in Sketch, that was different, but it really isn’t a make or break for me. It’s nice, convenient, and saved a few minutes here and there, but it isn’t something that I’ve been particularly frustrated at with PS.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/sketch/export.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of layers &quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Will it Blend?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the big question - I’ll certainly use it on the next project, until it can’t do what I need and then I’ll switch to PS. I may learn a few more keyboard shortcuts, and a few more tricks. In the end it saved me time vs costing me it - but that’ll be on a case-by-case basis. I do a good amount of concepting in program (things like “how does this look here”, and “let’s try this”), so it certainly helps with an iterative workflow, that seeks to get digital as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.haaans.com/7-sketch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.haaans.com/7-sketch/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>7 Productivity Apps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bagcheck was a startup (founded by Luke W., and later acquired by Twitter) that was dedicated to the concept of sharing your passions, or what’s in your bag. It was a really neat concept and a definite loss for the internet when it was taken down a few years ago. I most enjoyed checking out people’s default OS X setups, or the programs they couldn’t go without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same spirit of inspiration and discovery, I’m sharing the OS X productivity programs that I love. I could write pages on different OS X settings I prefer, but I’ll try and keep this to apps. Working in front-end design &amp;amp; development, I wouldn’t recommend these programs to everyone, but I can honestly say I’m a huge fan of them for my uses. Most all of the apps offer a freemium model, with a premium version well worth the cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;**Note: some of the awesome names of the companies producing the apps: AgileBits, Mizage, Running with Crayons, Noodelsoft&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Name Changer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;One of the timeless gems among the bunch, I couldn’t imagine clearing my desktop off without it. Programatic decisions explained in human terms for batch file renaming. Name changer does it all: appending, pre-pending, sequences, find a and replace, the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/namechanger.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of wunderlist&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free &lt;/span&gt;| Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mrrsoftware.com/namechanger/&quot;&gt;MRR Software&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1 Password&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;I’ve been a 1Password fan for a few years now, and it’s an irreplaceable part of my workflow. I tried out a few different services, including LastPass, native OS X keychain, google chrome keychain etc, but nothing touched the cross-platform/browser integration, that 1password offers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/1password.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of 1Password&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free - $50 &lt;/span&gt;| Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://agilebits.com/downloads&quot;&gt;AgileBits&lt;/a&gt; and on the App Store
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Handbrake&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;A longtime fan of the simplicity of HandBrake, I’ve used it countless times for (predominately) legal reasons. There’s no simpler way - that I know of - to rip/convert a dvd to a video file, and optimize it. The simple options and two step process had me before I even knew what the term ‘transcode’ meant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/handbrake.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of handbrake&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free &lt;/span&gt;| Available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://handbrake.fr/&quot;&gt;handbrake&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Alfred 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;The ultimate launcher for OSX - and it&amp;#39;s nothing like spotlight. 90% of Alfred’s usefulness comes from it’s ability to quickly automate and run tasks. For instance, we have an internal GitHub at Garmin - (we use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/software/stash?utm_source=bitbucket&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=homepage&amp;amp;utm_content=bitbucket_for_enterprises&quot;&gt;stash&lt;/a&gt;, by Atlasssian), and we have a workflow that searches all repos in our stash, and links you directly to the selected repo. Below are a few of my most used tasks:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/alfred.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of alfred&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ft&lt;/code&gt; - Immediately opens a terminal window with the current directory at your last used finder window. Conversely, &lt;code&gt;tf&lt;/code&gt; opens a finder at the current Terminal directory.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LeEnno/alfred-terminalfinder&quot;&gt;Check it out on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;hide&lt;/code&gt; - Hide Hidden files, show hidden files - instead of arduously running &lt;code&gt;defaults write com.apple.finder AppleShowAllFiles YES &amp;amp;&amp;amp; killall Finder&lt;/code&gt; in terminal I open alfred and type “hide” or &amp;quot;show&amp;quot;, the rest is handled.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BubiDevs/manage-hidden-files&quot;&gt;Also on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;edit&lt;/code&gt; - Edit Project, a custom workflow that I made that takes the currently selected folder in finder, opens it in sublime, as well as terminal and runs &lt;code&gt;grunt watch&lt;/code&gt; on the directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free - $14.99 &lt;/span&gt;| You’ll need the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alfredapp.com/powerpack/&quot;&gt;Power Pack&lt;/a&gt; ($14.99) to add/use custom workflows.
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Divvy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;Freemium software from Mizage for window management. I spend so time (albeit subconsciously) arranging the many windows I constantly have open. Attaching keyboard shortcuts to this has been huge, and with Divvy, it couldn’t be simpler, or allow you to get more specific with your window management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/divvy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of wunderlist&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free - $13.99 &lt;/span&gt;| Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://mizage.com/divvy/&quot;&gt;Mizage&lt;/a&gt;, or on the App store
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;The world is still searching for the perfect task/to do list fix to once and for all replace the sticky note, but in the mean time, Wunderlist as an acceptable middle grounds. It’s simple, integrated, connected (I can easily share lists with coworkers, or my wife), and extremely satisfying to check off items.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/wunderlist.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of wunderlist&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free &lt;/span&gt;| Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wunderlist.com/&quot;&gt;Wunderlist&lt;/a&gt; or on the App Store
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;app&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Hazel&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;first-paragraph&quot;&gt;Hazel is an app that one of my friends, &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewsaliga.com/&quot;&gt;Andrew Saliga&lt;/a&gt; led me on to. I’m not sure it contains any unique functionality, or anything you couldn’t accomplish with OSX’s built in Automator, but it certainly makes automation easier. You don’t need to know a language, or be a pro to run regular actions on folders, or tasks in general. For someone like me, that means it’s great for helping automatically organize and rename things like pictures by date, or keeping your downloads folder clean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img-content/productivity/hazel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of wunderlist&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dark&quot;&gt;Free trial - $29 &lt;/span&gt;| Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php&quot;&gt;Noodelsoft&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.haaans.com/7-productivity-apps/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.haaans.com/7-productivity-apps/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>